Follow your heart and nothing is impossible.
Thumbelina is a animation, fantasy, romance film directed by Don Bluth.
Born of a flower and growing to only a couple of inches tall, poor Thumbelina is worried she'll never meet
someone her own size, until she happens to catch the eye of Prince Cornelius of the Fairies.
Just as soon as she finds love, however, it's torn
away when she's kidnapped by Ms.
Now Thumbelina has to escape Ms.
Toad's grasp and search for Prince Cornelius.
Luckily, there's a whole city of animals willing to help.
Thumbelina (voice), played by Jodi Benson.
Jacquimo (voice), played by Gino Conforti.
Mother (voice), played by Barbara Cook.
Hero / Reverend Rat (voice), played by Will Ryan.
Queen Tabitha (voice), played by June Foray.
King Colbert (voice), played by Kenneth Mars.
Thumbelina (also known as Hans Christian Andersen's Thumbelina) is a 1994 American independent animated musical fantasy
film directed by Don Bluth and Gary Goldman, based on the story Thumbelina by Hans Christian Andersen.
The film stars the voices of Jodi Benson and Gary Imhoff, with supporting roles from Gino Conforti,
Joe Lynch, Gilbert Gottfried, Kenneth Mars, Carol Channing, Barbara Cook, and Charo.
Thumbelina was produced by Don Bluth Ireland Ltd.
and distributed by Warner Bros.
under its Family Entertainment imprint.
The film was released in theaters on March 30, 1994, to mixed reviews from film critics, and
became a box-office failure, grossing $17 million against a $28 million budget.
The film explores themes of witch, france, widow, feminism, fairy.
The tone is emotional.